Hey everybody, welcome to this week in
Stardust. We're about to take you to
Osaka, Japan for Jason's live chat with
Yuki Sherado. He's the managing director
of the Tech Stars Tokyo Accelerator.
They're going to have a fascinating deep
dive on what's going on in the Japan
startup scene. Then Jason and Yuki hear
some pitches from some amazing Japanese
founders. Thanks to Jetro for powering
this awesome event. Enjoy the show.
>> How's everybody doing?
>> Oh, now it's good. Now it's good. up
top.
This is a very beautiful room. If only
it had a good view.
Wow, what a view. Incredible. Um, it's
great to be back in Japan. I have been
coming every six months now. Uh I am
very lucky because um
uh Jetro
asked me last year, hey would you uh
come to Japan and bring your founder
university and bring it to Japan and I
said uh
twist my arm
and they twisted it and I went oh okay
I'll come. Um because I love coming to
Japan and I've been coming for many
years. Uh maybe 25 years. Uh and the
first time I came, I stayed in uh
Rapangi at a hotel that was $80 a night.
And uh I got into the bed and then I
tried to figure out where to put my bag,
but the bag wasn't enough room between
the bed and the walls. So I had it like
hanging off the bed and I could touch
one side of the room. I could touch the
wall and then when I leaned over at my
bed, I could touch the other side and I
fell in love with Japan. Uh I got up at
5 in the morning and went to this Giji
fish market
and uh then I ate everything.
And now between my trips here, I have a
bot. I have a Grock bot and I take
screenshots and articles and I just give
it to my bot. I used to write everything
down in a book. Now I just give it to my
bot and I say when I'm in Japan um
uh make me an HTML file of all the
places by neighborhood and then I just
walk around
uh and I get to uh eat and we do
something called a bang bang bang bang.
This is something that um chefs in
America came up with. When you come
somewhere that's really great, you don't
just want to have one breakfast. You
want to have at least two.
And you don't want to have one lunch.
You want to have two lunches. And for
dinner, you really can't get by with
less than three.
And so what we do is I come with my
friends and um we'll go have uh the
pancakes at Bill's and then the French
toast at Center Bakery and then we'll
get ramen and then we'll get tonkatu and
then we'll get tempora just and we walk
around uh and everybody who's an
entrepreneur who I bring to Japan gets
very excited
um because they can't believe that
everybody in Japan is an entrepreneur.
for everybody in Japan is a founder. You
didn't know this, but when you go to the
Tonkatu place and you watch them work,
they care like a founder cares about
their startup. Every detail, lots of
focus. And Kaizen getting a little bit
better each time. Getting a little bit
better each time. And so, uh, I told
Jetro, "We can do Founder University as
long as it starts in January." They
said, "January? Why January?" I said,
"Well, I have to go to Hokkaido and
ski."
So, one week in Tokyo, it's a little
cold. And then I go to Hokkaido, and
it's very cold, but there's so much
incredible snow. Uh, and then in the
summer, we also have found university.
or twice a year and we have our second
cohort. It's going very well. Um we're
getting to meet so many great
entrepreneurs and they asked me to come
to Osaka. I've never been here. I've
been to Miyazaki. Uh but my first time
in Osaka. Uh this is a beautiful city.
Um how many people are from Osaka here?
How many people? Okay, not too many. How
many people are from Tokyo? Great. How
many people from the United States?
Okay, great. Awesome. Uh, well, it's
going to be great for us to hang out a
little bit. I love meeting founders and
helping them. Two of my team members are
here. Ismael is maybe outside and Lucas
is here, who's the CTO for my venture
firm.
Um, and we're going to talk tonight
about being an entrepreneur.
And um, I have a great guest
from Tech Stars and we're going to take
pitches as well. some of the tech stars
companies and then just some random
companies that applied. And this is
going to be a lot of fun because this is
a safe space.
We're going to give very, very,
very candid feedback.
This is something that's not very
Japanese. I learned I'm from Brooklyn.
In Brooklyn, when you do something
that's stupid, everybody looks at you
and said, "Wow, that was very stupid.
You're extremely dumb. Why do you keep
doing so many stupid things, Jason?" And
then I'd say, "I I I don't know. That
was really stupid. I'll never do that
again. Thank you." In Japan, they say,
"And
if you do something really bad, I had to
explain this." They say,
"I understand that this is an extremely
dramatic way to say, "Why are you so
stupid?"
Is it correct? This means
you're an idiot.
you're doing something that everybody
else understands you should not do. And
I said, "Well, how would I know I'm not
supposed to walk across this beautiful
grass lawn?" And they said, "The sign
that says do not walk in. This happened
to me. I was in a park and it happened."
Okay. Uh so I'll just tell you briefly
about Founder University. We uh had an
incredible experience.
Our venture capital firm launch uh we
make 100 investments a year. We have 20
people. Uh and we found out that when we
would get well over 10,000 applications
for funding a year, half of them were
not yet incorporated. And we keep seeing
this trend in the age of AI especially.
The company has not incorporated.
there's two or three people but they
have a finished product and it's awesome
and they don't need money and they might
even have a customer or two or people
using the product and I say well how do
you take their money and oh we're not
charging yet or um I put it on my
personal Stripe account from another
thing uh I was another project I was
doing and so we saw all that energy and
we had our accelerator and there's tech
stars and Y combinator and many other
great programs so we said what if we
created something for for the
accelerator founder university 12 weeks
twice a week tactical and practical
talks tactical how to get things done
practical easy to apply and so we
started this program we've now done it
12 times in the United States right now
we're doing our second cohort uh in
Japan and in January we start the third
one japanfounderun
university if you want to apply it's
going to start in January I don't I
don't know why January is such a random
month. We started in January again. Wow,
that's crazy. That's the best month for
skiing in Hokkaido. What a coincidence.
Um, so you should all um apply for that.
Okay, so uh let me bring up Yuki
Shirato. Yuki, come on up. Let's give
him a big round of applause.
And as is the tradition, you and I are
going to do a karaoke duet.
>> You've picked the song.
>> I will pick a song. Yes. No,
>> I'm joking. I'm not going to do a song.
>> Maybe later. You never know.
>> You get to sit. I will relax.
>> Tell everybody how long has Tech Stars
uh been in Japan and uh tell us about
the program here and when you joined.
>> Techstars Tokyo started in 2024, 3 years
ago. So I've been the managing director
since the inception. Uh so sort of like
inaugural uh MD uh and then we are
currently running the third program. Uh
and then we accept 12 companies a year.
Six from Japan and six from known uh
outside Japan actually. Uh and then also
when I say Japan doesn't have to be
Japanese founders in Japan. So some of
them are actually founded by foreigners
in Japan where the Japanese founders uh
who live abroad and then started a
company mostly in California in the
United States.
>> Bringing people um to Japan is a big
focus of the uh government today. Maybe
you could talk a little bit about how
that's changed over time. It used to be
a little bit hard 20 years ago to come
here as an American.
>> Right. That that's absolutely right. So
we have two goals and and then texture
Tokyo is uh sponsored by Jetro as well
as uh Japanese uh government in general
cabinet office ministry of com trade and
industry and then Tokyo motor government
and uh uh their uh two goals are one
Japanese startups going global so you
help the Japanese startups going global
and then the other uh goal is to entice
the foreign founders come to Japan uh so
Japan market entry and foreign direct
investment um
>> they don't need to speak Japanese.
>> No.
>> So,
>> my program is English.
>> They can learn.
>> Yes.
>> There's some very important words you
need to learn.
>> Yes.
>> Um, my favorite is
>> which I say increasingly as I have beers
even more gruff, right?
>> Is my favorite word. Excuse me.
>> Yeah.
>> Is my favorite word,
>> right?
>> Only because I like the sound of it. Um,
so I think one of the key things we
should talk about is the Japanese
entrepreneur
and how they look at
uh starting a company
in Japan which is an amazing market 100
million uh customers customers have a
lot of money they're very techsavvy they
want to try new things they're excited
they're enthusiastic
and for many years,
a lot of Japanese companies have been
content with staying on the island,
>> but that's something I think we want to
see change a little bit. So maybe talk a
little bit about the mindset of Japanese
entrepreneurs and how you work with them
to maybe start thinking about America,
Europe, Middle East, etc. I think uh the
cultural shift in entrepreneurship in
Japan uh is uh hard to change but
gradually changing as you mentioned. Um
I think we need uh like a heroes or role
models who uh have been successful as
entrepreneurs and become serial
entrepreneurs uh or uh very publicly
speaking about their experiences. Um so
I think uh things are are generally uh
gradual unfortunately. I I think um the
the entrepreneurship spirit amongst
Japanese people are still pretty low as
compared in United States. Uh um uh the
Tokyo or Japan uh you know there are a
lot of uh rankings of entrepreneurship
and startups and and Japan is always
around like between um 10 and 15th uh
spot which is great. uh used to be like
30 or 40 so it's going up and up but I
think there is a a huge uh sort of like
you know um the hurdle to to overcome uh
to get to San Fran, New York and London.
Uh so yeah, I'm I'm seeing a lot of uh
Japanese uh top talent uh becoming
entrepreneurs uh because mostly um kind
of they lost hope on the long like
lifetime employment or you know the
illusion of uh you know big corporations
uh just being forever. Um but um I think
it is still a challenge
>> and that concept of working at a big
company forever still exists in Japan
but parents are now maybe thinking a
little differently about what they wish
for their sons and daughters. Yeah. They
used to maybe when I first started
coming here 25 or 30 years ago, the idea
that you would skip working for a big
company to start your own company was
very scary. It was considered a bad
idea,
>> right?
>> But here we are in 2026. I think many
parents would rather see their uh son or
daughter start a company first, give it
a shot, knowing well the big company
will still be there. Am I correct in
>> uh my view of this?
>> I think
>> it's okay if I'm not. My perception is a
bit biased, but I've been talking to
folks and
>> yeah,
>> I don't know if it's everyone, but it
does seem to be changing a bit.
>> Yes, it is. It is definitely changing. I
I agree. Uh but I think relatively
speaking, it's still uh pretty
conservative. Um so for example if you
fail as an entrepreneur and and then you
spend like I don't know five years uh
and then you're I don't know mid to late
20s uh where would you go? So there are
a lot of Japanese corporates who take
the mikaria people now uh and then they
are more tolerant of you know failed
entrepreneurs or uh whoever uh you know
challenged uh themselves to do something
else and then trying to come back. Um
but I think there are still a little bit
of con conservatism uh amongst uh
corporate people uh who prefer to have
someone right after undergrad and then
you know stay with the company for a
long time and then there are some uh
very successful Japanese companies uh of
course right like Sony and then Mubishi
and then so uh it is not um yeah uh and
unreasonable for parents to think that
you know they should work for the the
big corporations. either
>> it's reasonable, but now in pop culture,
they're starting to see examples of
what's possible. Um and the skills and
the craftsmanship here even if uh folks
maybe don't believe they're
entrepreneurs when we come from America
we go wow you understand as a culture
product market fit PMF the hardest thing
in the world feels like it is one of the
core tenants one of the core skill sets
of the Japanese people is product market
fit
>> right
>> it's inherent in almost every
interaction I have here so maybe
>> talk a little bit about where that
starts in school with parents h how does
product market fit become such a deep
and important part of the Japanese
culture
>> well that's a difficult question but I
think uh it comes down to education
especially the for young children I
think uh they learn um um in a young age
um like the rules of society uh and then
they uh uh behave in certain way to uh
kind of create a harmony and and uh I
think it's uh just comes down to like
how you educate children. I think uh
there is no right or wrong curriculum
for any school. uh and then uh
I don't know. I think that's that's a
very difficult question.
>> I have some ideas about why.
>> Okay.
>> I think if you see people taking pride
in their work
>> um from a very young age and you assume
that's what's expected
that if you were going to make the
coffee, you would do it as best you can.
And if you were uh going to do any other
job, the expectation is even if nobody's
watching to do it well,
>> to do it to the best of your ability and
to take some amount of pride in it.
>> I think it's just embedded in how what
you see,
>> right? And in other cultures, you might
see people not caring as much. Uh, and
if somebody were to throw some um litter
on the floor in America, people just
walk by.
>> Right.
>> Here, if you were to do that,
it would be a big conversation. Yeah.
>> Yep. Yep. Yeah. They they definitely
take pride in their work. Um, like, you
know, from uh I don't know, the
conductor of train to uh the garbage
collector to primary school teacher um
to yeah, the ceramic artist. It's like
everyone uh cares about like like their
attention to detail is surmount I think.
So that's that's uh for sure. Uh how
they are nurtured that way is a very
difficult question. I really don't know
why. Well, and then I think maybe the
counter is maybe an intolerance for
failure
>> and maybe a little bit of shame if you
don't do it well, which then might lead
people to take a little less risk on the
margins as opposed to in America. Yeah.
>> Where if I said fake it till you make
it.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, just believe that you're the
CEO of a big corporation
>> and people will treat you like one.
People go, "Yeah, that's a good advice."
>> Yeah. maybe not so much here. I'm here
with Keith Pius, the founder of
Lightfield. They are an AI native CRM
that builds and updates itself in real
time from your email, your calendar,
your Slack, your meeting notes, all
those things that you keep misplacing.
Welcome to the program, Keith.
>> Uh, great to be here.
>> What novel use cases have you seen your
customers use with Lightfield? Because
some of them are obvious. Hey, I'm
selling SAS software. Hey, I'm selling a
product or service into corporate
America. uh and it's pretty you know
standard process at this point in 2026
but once you introduce AI into this you
can get really creative so what creative
uses have people found inside of
lightfield
>> I'll start with uh finding new customers
the first thing is we found that it's so
easy to build these automations in light
field where you are scraping different
websites and looking at different data
sources then giving it to you know a
high parameter model to to reason
through that you can find new customers
in ways that you couldn't using
traditional data sources. Uh so we have
folks that are uh scraping clinical
trials websites, you know, or scraping
firms that have uh active litigation
matters, you know, from government
websites.
and then uh using light field enrichment
to uh connect those people to companies
or companies to people uh and then
sending them highly tailored uh
personalized emails.
>> Everybody go check out heightfield.app.
>> Yeah, I think the that's right. Um I
think I heard analogy that uh everyone
wears a lab coat in Japan. So, it's like
a white coat that if you make a mistake,
you get tainted. You know, you get like
a little bit of
>> Oh, that's
>> you know, red ink or, you know, blue ink
or whatever. And then you don't want to
get a lot of like, you know, stains uh
throughout your life. So, if you die and
then with a clean white lab coat, your
life is like, you know, impeccable. Uh
as opposed to, you know, you get a lot
of failures.
>> It's completely backwards. Each of those
blotches tells a story.
>> Yeah. That's actually
>> that's how Americans Yeah. would think
>> you would look at the um if you were a
cowboy
>> and you saw the boots and the boots had
some cuts in them and
>> if the leather jacket was rough and had
a hole or your jeans were ripped, that's
a story. Yeah,
>> that's a great moment where you learn
something, right? Yeah.
>> So,
>> that's actually a very good point
because Japanese people are really bad
at storytelling. Uh so, they have a lot
of stories, right? But they never tell
their stories. Uh so this is completely
different from startups but uh if uh if
I may. Um so I was helping this uh
Japanese um uh client uh of mine and um
long story but he was uh deposed uh
because uh they were uh allegedly uh
stealing some uh patent uh from another
US company. uh but uh he actually uh
went you know up to the podium not
podium like the stand and then spoke
about it and then he was like naturally
answering the you know the the opposing
council's course examination and then it
was about the cinnamon uh so there was a
a very special molecular um like you
know elements and the cinnamon that he
found and then they created this like
you know interesting uh products uh but
you know this US company sued them
Right. And then he went on to the stand
and then cross examination. He naturally
said like you know I'm very confident. I
developed this. I discovered this. This
is my product. This is my work. You know
this is my life work. I've been working
in this 30 years. How can you even like
you know doubt and whatever right? And
then how can you say that is like oh I
have a daughter like 18 year old. I
named her cinnamon because you know I
this like dedicated my life to this. So
I even named my daughter Cinnamon. So
like it was this like kind of and
crossing examiner like opposing council
just was like a movie
>> like shocked and like Yeah. So
>> case closed.
>> Exactly. So I think that some Japanese
people just take years and decades of
one thing and then make it really
perfect. So
>> and so how are the applications going?
Are you getting a good number of
applications and then when they come in
what do they need help with in the
program? what are the things where they
uh just don't know what to do uh they
don't have exposure to it.
>> So the vast majority of applications
actually come from outside Japan
uh which says something um but uh yeah
we are getting uh thousands of
applications uh which is uh which is
great uh a lot of uh non-Japanese people
want to move to Japan and try out uh to
get some Japanese capital or work with
Japanese businesses or even hire top
talent. Um but uh again I think the
challenge is the Japanese side, the
Japanese entrepreneurs and whatnot. But
I think the government is doing a great
job and supporting the community and
ecosystem. Uh and then I think uh you've
done a a great service to Japan like you
know founder university is amazing. I
think they are a great catalyst.
>> I think some of ours have applied and
maybe even gotten into text which is
great. We're a feeder for you guys.
>> Yes. and and then actually the and also
the um you know uh vice versa I think
the texters graduates went to launch.
>> Oh fantastic. Yes we did have yeah thank
you so much. Yeah. So I think you're
drain because you've done so much for
Silicon Valley and then you know like
startup ecosystem around the world right
globally and then you being like in
Japan and coming to Japan and helping
the Japanese founders and ecosystem is a
a really boost uh huge boost to the
community itself. film.
>> And you have a gift for me. I
understand. He's he didn't tell
everybody, but he's brought my passport.
So, I have a Japanese passport now. Have
I earned it yet?
>> Maybe a little more work.
>> Yes. Maybe five more years.
>> A little more. Five more years I get
that Japanese passport. I have a
long-term goal.
>> Very hard for an American to get that
Japanese passport, but who knows? Maybe
if I help with a unicorn, then I will
earn it.
>> Yes.
>> Uh, okay. Speaking of helping founders,
we're going to start taking some
pitches. Yes.
>> Okay. So, these are some of your
companies
>> and I'm going to see them for the first
time I believe. And so, let's bring up
our first company.
>> Um, hi everyone. My name is Lamia and
I'm the co-founder of VD Labs where we
built Seeker. Seeker is a spatial
intelligence layer for complex indoor
spaces. So, with Seeker, we can find
your exact position just by your phone's
camera. Its accuracy is down to the
centimeter level. No hardware
installation required. and we work best
where there's no GPS.
Precise positioning is still a
challenge, especially for industries
such as indoor wayfinding, last mile
deliveries, and also physical AI bots.
GPS will help you find the building, but
it can't tell you which floor you're on.
So, this is how Seeker works. We come
in, we take a 3D scan of the place. Our
algorithm turns that scan into a precise
map and then we go live where visitors
get the live navigation and venue
operators get the live movement data.
We build maps six times faster and in
real time. And we do this with LAR or
just photos or even just videos of the
space. And what we do is clearly like
something that engineers don't have to
manually annotate because our visual
positioning system makes and takes care
of repeated structures, closed loops,
and also um narrow spaces.
So, we're live at the Hong Kong
International Airport where it took us
two weeks to go from scanning to
deployment. We're also covering the
plug-and-play Silicon Valley Summit
where 4,000 exhibition goers will be
using Seeker to navigate the 3-day
conference.
Our technology is so precise that even a
blind user can navigate just by our
audio and haptic feedback and you know
operators like venue operators get
realtime data such as visitor flow,
dwell time and also dynamic rerouting
options.
So, the indoor navigation space is a $
31 billion opportunity and we are
positioned to capture 1,800 venues. That
opens up revenue of about $500 million.
So, we built Seeker because we've got
family members that are visually
impaired and we wanted them to navigate
indoor spaces uh independently. But what
we've built is one map that both people
and machines can read. Uh we've won
Forbes and CES for our innovation. We
were also featured in CNN just last
month. So we are seeker where GPS stops
seekers start. Thank you so much.
>> And it's Lamia.
>> Yes,
>> Lamia. Okay. Do you want candid
super candid or jcal candid?
>> I I will go for jcal candid.
>> Okay. So I'm gonna
>> I'm scared. I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
>> I mean you could but I could go up and
down. Uh I always like since we're all
founders here, I'll tell you all the
good and the bad. Yeah. Okay.
>> So um this pitch we've seen over the
years as a known problem.
>> So everybody knows this is a problem. We
all experience this problem. But what
investors are thinking about, we have
one here. Where's the investor? He ran.
Oh no, he's here. So he's still here. Um
he's thinking, um oh, this is
interesting technology. Um there's no
business here. It happens to every
business at some point. You're nearing
the end of the month or maybe it's the
quarter and your sales team is at risk
of missing their quota. You could waste
days pulling together data from across
the entire organization. Or you could
just ask Rippling AI. Ripling's already
built on your real-time people and
business data obviously. So Rippling AI
can pull metrics from both Rippling and
your CRM into a meeting ready dashboard.
See exactly how close you are to hitting
that quota. Break down your revenue by
region or sales rep or more, all in just
seconds with Rippling AI. Look, you're
running a company. You're busy. You have
critical questions that you need
immediate answers to. And you can't just
file a ticket and wait a week for your
team to get around to sending you a
report. And you don't want to sit around
waiting for reports. You need an
actionable insight right now. So, if
you're ready to rule your business, head
to rippling.ai/twist AI/Tist to get the
only AI built to give you full
visibility and let you take complex
actions across your startup and you
reinforced that unintentionally because
you didn't address the business case
here. What is the business case for
this? How are you going to make that
$500 million? And then there were things
that when you talk about press, CNN,
Forbes, that's a soft
like metric.
Take that out. Talk about a customer if
you have a limited amount of time. And
so that's really just the focus of the
presentation. Then you had the charming
story. Hey, somebody in the family is
blind or impaired. Okay, that's fine as
like a starting point, but again,
without the business being in there now,
some investors, like he's pretty
hardcore. Um, he's thinking, "Oh, these
people want to save the world. That's
amazing, but I would never invest in
somebody who wants to save the world. I
want somebody who wants to build a
unicorn and get to a hundred million in
revenue as quick as possible." So, I
think I'll give you a shot at it right
now. The $ 31 billion the TAM is like a
topdown TAM number.
>> Correct.
>> We don't like those. What we train
people in founder university is to build
the bottom up TAM. And your two examples
an airport. Okay. And then the other one
like a conference that was almost
proving to me as an investor like oh
maybe there's no customer here. So take
a second. Did you figure out a business
model here yet or are you still in the
trying to figure out how you might
monetize this? That is actually a really
good question and in fact one of the
reasons we're with tech stars is that
we're trying to explore the Japan market
but I will tell you this um we've
received an impressive amount of
inbounds and they come from different
verticals. So of course we started with
the airports but I am getting inbounds
from amusement parks that want to make
you know customer service experience a
lot better. They want KPI in a flash and
that's where the importance of the
dashboard comes. By no means is
point-to-point navigation our remote.
It's the data here that is at play. The
data of okay, where are my customers?
Where are they spending more time in?
Are they buying anything in the luxury
stores of the airports? So, that is
where the business is.
>> Great. And that's where I thought you
might go.
>> Okay.
>> Um, which is awesome. And then when you
go down that maze, then the next thing
is you have to have done the research.
>> Yes. of all the other people who have
tried that as well and where they wound
up. Correct. Company Density IO that
we've been investors in for 10 years.
They use sensors in spaces to count
people and then they sell it to office
spaces so they can, you know, um tell
you where there's open desks. They will
tell the cleaning crew which conference
rooms have to be cleaned. But if nobody
was in the conference room for the last
24 hours, that they will have the
cleaning people skip that conference
room. Right. Yes. So that area is a
known area as well and there's a couple
of companies that have been
venturebacked that do video. So you're
in the idea maze. You've obviously got
technical chops. I think it's time now
you've proven you can build a product,
but you're going to have to be cutthroat
about how you're going to make money and
you really have to know all the people
in the possible places. Don't be passive
about it and wait for inbound. What I
hope you do is you go to 10 people, 20
people. You show them the technology and
then you interview them about what their
issues are etc. and try to find
something that is a hair on fire problem
like a real problem. You hear vitamins
and painkiller. This discussed and you
you've heard this as well, I'm sure.
Like right now feels like a vitamin
which is if you skip your vitamins, you
know, you you for you might skip your
vitamins for an entire week and not
notice. But if you skip a painkiller and
you've got a twisted ankle, you're going
to know in six hours you forgot to take
it. So that's what I want you to do
next. Okay, great job. Let's give her a
big round of applause.
>> Yuki, was I too hard? Was that
>> amazing feedback?
>> Was it too hard?
>> I don't care.
>> I want you to get the hard I want you to
get the hard stuff. No, I do care. I
care enough to give the brutal candid
advice. And you know what? I'm I'm often
wrong, but
not that often.
Like, um I I can always tell how
investors are going to interpret it and
the investors don't tell you the truth,
but you always have me to tell you the
truth. Yuki will tell you the truth as
well. Uh, investor in blue. Investor in
blue.
Did any of what I say, did any of the
like handicapping I did about how
investors would interpret this parallel
what you were thinking?
>> Yeah.
>> Who are the clients? Exactly. Boom. Um
and so one of the things that'll happen
is you go to conferences
uh everybody wants to support founders
and then the investors want to support
founders and there's no upside for an
investor doing what I just did which is
being brutally candid like Jcal level
candid because what if she gets upset at
me and she's like Jay Cal's a jerk I'm
never going to let him invest in my
company when I do figure it out I'm
going to send him an email when I sell
my company for a billion dollars and and
let him know he missed out, which I do
get those emails sometimes.
>> Arabat helps electronics manufacturers
to recover valuable materials from their
waste. Hello everyone, I am Ralph, co
and co-founder of Arabat. Batteries,
capacitors, magnets, the building blocks
of AI, energy, and defense. They all
depend on critical minerals. We can
secure more than 200 million kilograms.
That's the amount of e-waste generated
by AI data center alone every year by
and of the rare earth locked inside it
90% of the world's recycling capacity is
still concentrated in one country US
Japan no China electronic manufacturers
face the same problem disposal cost
supply risk and compliance all at once.
Our solution to all of that just an
orange. More precisely, instead of using
expensive and harsh chemicals to do the
recycling, we just use orange pills and
other cheap agri food waste to recover
the critical minerals from the
electronics. Our patented technology
takes in e-waste and scrap and using
more than 50 fruits or vegetable. It can
selectively recover critical minerals
for the industry like lithium, cobalt,
nickel and rare earth. More precisely,
we open the hardware. We crush it and we
mix it with biomass to get finally all
the crystals of such critical minerals
ready to sell for the industry. And we
do this 60% cheaper, 50% cleaner and
also twice as fast to permit compared to
any other competitors. Tauden, a
multi-billion dollar Japanese company,
is already testing our solution under a
recently signed strategic agreement.
Real NCA batteries, real capacitors,
local Japanese biomass. Uh to date we
have already two patents a pilot plant
under development and now we are raising
to scale up our biiobased approach
worldwide because our future shouldn't
depend on who owns the mines. It should
depend on what grows nearby because
money doesn't grow on trees. Critical
materials do like simple oranges. Thank
you for your attention.
>> Wow. You found this company, Yuki. You
found it.
>> No, I didn't.
>> I want to know if he applies.
>> He applied. Yeah. Great presentation.
You're a natural presenter. Um and um
you have something that nobody here has
ever seen. Has anybody here ever heard
of this technique for
Were you in the program with him or are
you a biologist?
You met him before?
>> Ah, got it. Yes. But nobody knew about
this until you did it. So this puts you
in a very unique startup category which
is you're like this very unique like a
unicorn without the revenue and the
valuation. But um so when in a pitch
contest like this or meeting investors
you're going to need to after you get
them intrigued like I'm intrigued right
now and other investors might be
intrigued. You're going to have to
really educate us. How does this get to
market? The go-to market is going to be
the big question here. Is there somebody
who really needs this? And that's where
pilots come in. And when you do pilots,
you really want paid pilots. You don't
want to hire just anybody. You want to
work with the very top, most skilled
people who really understand every
aspect of the work they're doing. But
seeking out a crew of specialists, well,
that's its own full-time job. And you've
got a startup to run. Now, there's a
solution. Upwork. When you make a
podcast like we do, there are so many
different kinds of jobs that need to be
done behind the scenes. Every platform
where we post videos needs its own kind
of content and different editors
specialize in different kinds of videos.
When we need somebody to massively boost
our following on Instagram reels or
start knocking out Tik Tok edits that
will hit perfectly on your for you feed,
we find these freelancers on Upwork.
Now, we want to help you try it out for
yourself. Visit upwork.com right now and
post your job for free. That's
upwork.com to connect with top talent
ready to help your business grow.
upw.com
upwork.com. So anybody can get a free
pilot. You have a pilot, right?
>> We have uh we have done free pilots and
now it's a paid pilot from Japanese
customer.
>> Got it. But you did free pilots before
that. How many free pilots?
>> Some free pilots. Two.
>> Two of them. Okay. So, what we're always
contending with in our accelerator and
then in Foundry University is getting
people from the free pilot mode to the
paid pilot mode. Um, and and what's the
ballpark figure for the pilot? How much
are they putting at risk?
>> $50k.
>> Okay. And that's for three-month pilot
or something.
>> Um, more six months, six months.
>> And what will, if it succeeds,
what will be the outcome? And then what
will you charge them for the next either
pilot or the first um deployment?
>> They told us that are interested at
opening new business initiatives around
recycling because they are losing money
from their defective capacitors and so
they told about licensing or joint
venture. This was what they said. And so
you're in that um discovery phase, but
the technology works. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. On lab and also pilot
already tested our own.
>> So we'll assume this product's going to
work. Is it cost effective? Like does it
actually recover enough materials to
make it profitable, very profitable,
somewhat profitable. Tell us about the
profitability. uh so profitable
especially when the feed stock to
recycle includes radars like ceramic
capacitor present in each each
smartphone or magnet waste and in our
case we are cost effective why because
biomass is cheap the maximum cost could
be one ton one $100 per ton
>> where are all these uh materials being
sent today to landfills to Africa
>> yeah landfills and China because China,
for example, has the most important um
industry in recycling, and they still
use traditional technology.
>> Could you just go to the landfills and
say, "We will pay you half of whatever
we recover and we just want the 50-year
license for all the garbage coming
here."
>> Yeah, we are thinking about that. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, if this is so profitable,
maybe you need to just have people give
you the material and then you give them
money or find out where that material is
and then you buy the rights to it. So,
you're not dependent on this electronics
company getting through a pilot. Like if
you actually know that there's, you
know, rare earths in this garbage dump
in Japan where they're putting it onto a
barge and sending it to China, you need
to intercept it before it goes to China
and say, "Hey, we'll take it cuz they
sell it to China or they pay China to
take it."
>> They they sell to China.
>> They sell used electronics to China to
rip it powder from electronics. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Interesting. Very interesting
business. Okay, let's give him a big
round of applause.
Thank you very much.
>> So this is I think Yuki a really
interesting company. Maybe you could say
a few words about it. Um and what you
think they need to do next as well.
>> Yeah, I mean they are selected in my
invested company. I hope they do well.
But I think your uh feedback was
extremely helpful. Uh and then in Arab
cases I agree it's a very unique
proposition. So very few people actually
understand that the value and then and
you know GTM and and all that. So I
think that's the challenge I think they
will face and then LA's case I think
like you said it's a known problem. So
they need to find you know the
>> yes two when you look at the two
different startups one of them is doing
something that is a known problem we
know some people have tried the other
one is like okay that's very weird we've
never even heard of this and you have to
understand that there's going to be
different benchmarks for what's going to
be expected if this problem is a known
problem well we expect you better have
like a good solution here and you better
have a really good idea about the
business plan when it's the first time
you hear about it's nent you may give
them a little bit more breathing room to
figure it out right there might be a
little more tolerance from investors
>> hi I'm Takua and the co-founder of asset
hub and we are making the 3D AI agent
for IP content
so at first uh the 3D model in
entertainment that is the biggest cost
so as for example for gaming it's
account for 50% of whole budget so that
everyone use the 3D foundational model
to make assets better. It doesn't work
for important context like IP character
that for example uh this model is made
by foundational model but it doesn't
work for IP holders because a proportion
of rebon is not same with a concept
right size bigger left is smaller
something like that so the IP is a set
of those kind of the uh local rule it's
not uh exports publicly right so that's
why just using the foundational model
trained by public data doesn't work. So
uh we uh develop the assets hub. Uh this
is our AI agent for making the high
level IP contents. So at first our agent
take image and they analyze okay what
type of image need to be prepared for 3D
AI separate the parts and then check the
consistency with the original inputs and
then generate 3D model with function
model and later to make it usable
compose them into single character by
referring to the original concept. So
while maintain the original uh taste. So
um by doing this we can automate the
entire process for making the quad
important characters. So uh we applied
this method for actual client and then
the client was making uh the anime
contents and then okay they spend at
least around a week to make single
character but now it's less than a day
and even more AI can do it parally right
so it's quite a faster and then cheaper
and then uh so far uh okay we earned
around 290k
annual run rate and the wide work with
the top IP contents and then we have
many Japanese clients and also as a
pipeline we are going to have a more US
side enterprise too. So uh our business
model uh at first uh we introduce the
FDE model. So uh by directly working
with IP holder we customize our agent
and then uh after that um we can export
those kind of things as a software. So
just sometimes a global user can use a
self sub style or just we sometimes do
the uh case IP licensing business uh by
giving the IP customized agent which is
acquired by the FD process.
So uh this is our go to market. So
simply say what we going to do is IP
rollup business. So at first uh okay we
can reduce the cost of main content
something like okay hierarchy okay they
have so many media right so anime gaming
or something everything use 3D model so
we op optimize the cost of them and then
once we could have agents that even we
do a more licensing business I mean the
uh just export this top grade IP agent
to every creators even UGC India
something so anyway yeah by making the
uh C top customized agent uh by IP
holders uh we can expand IP revenue even
we can take revenue share from the
contents too. So uh the only asset type
does it so uh there are the foundational
model company or some AI uh outsourcing
company too but most of them focusing on
more casual asset creations. So uh in
Japan so many IP content creators and
then uh there so many enterprise want to
work with startups. So that's why uh we
could have this wedge by working with
them. So yeah uh time is at first uh we
want to replace a 3D artist labor cost.
So it's there are around 30k artist in
the world and then the cost is around
the average $80k something. So it's a
$25 billion and even more if we can
expand the IP revenue share with IP roof
style uh it's could be six billion. So
it's around $30 billion time. Um and
then uh so we're going to achieve the
$und00 million of with this timeline. So
uh just within uh four years uh we
expand FDE and also the IP revenue share
initial model and after that yeah by
2034 we'd like that to $100 million.
Yeah. And our team is a ser founders uh
from entertainment and gaming. So uh my
previously uh my uh I co-ounded Gaudi
and that raised $70 million and they're
working with uh Japanese IP content uh
Sony Band something and then we also did
IP roper business and then Jonathan is
in San Francisco and exist founder in
gaming field and Android is also the uh
president founder of the sub company. So
we combine those expertise in this
company and then try achieving the kind
of biggest outcomes uh from there. So
yeah that's all. So thank you for
listening. Let me make sure I understand
the business. You have a tool that
instead of making 3D models in CAD tools
or however Pixar makes them or Hello
Kitty makes them, you make an AI version
of that that's really good and fast and
allows people to make those models uh
maybe 12 times faster. If I got it
right, 10 12 times faster. Then if you
can do it faster, then you can export
those and when somebody licenses Hello
Kitty to put it on a t-shirt or in a
video game or whatever, you can give
them the the assets faster and more
efficiently. Yeah.
>> Yes. Exactly. So uh at first uh so uh
it's beyond just a replacement to cat or
something. I mean the artist workflow of
course makes 3D model but after that
check the consistency quality. This is a
review process, right? So we cover end
to end process. So okay I take input
image as a design create a 3D model and
even giving the feedback and review and
the adjustment. So that's why it's a
beyond adjusted.
>> Got it. So the person who's making the
figurine has to make sure that the
person they're licensing it from agrees
that it's worthy of being produced.
>> Yes. So yeah the reason why the can say
many people cannot use IP is the
following the rule is really tough but
our agents replace the process
automatically by software
>> very interesting it's we don't have as
much of an IP business in the US or
Disney does Marvel and Star Wars we
don't um have as much I don't think but
I could be wrong as well um and the best
way to make money from this is to sell
people the software for you that's your
belief.
>> Yeah. And especially uh we expect a
global user use this IP agent. So I mean
the popularity of the Japanese anime IP
or something in uh UDC is getting
growing and even uh around the $500
million is a pirates version of the IP
contents in Roblox only blocks right so
that's why working with IP
>> you might have consumers making
characters for Roblox and they own that
IP and they can license it to some other
party.
>> Yes. So for for just example just make a
for example hierarchy agents for their
own original contents and then once we
could make a agent just uh distribute
this agent to UC creators of course they
can make UC content with a IP right and
then once they earn some revenue do
distribution something like a 20%
revenue or something
>> so I get Hello Kitty and I make a movie
or something a short film it will give
the license or give the licensing
revenue back to the owner. Yes,
something like that. Yes.
>> Ah, interesting. So, that's very
disruptive and interesting, I think. Um,
I literally just tweeted today people
have been making Marvel movies using
Sea, is it Sea Dance?
>> Sea dance.
>> Seance, we don't have it in the United
States. Yeah, the Chinese one. So,
people are making because they don't
respect the IP. They're making these
Marvel ones. And I said, Marvel should
put this into or Disney should put a
Marvel shorts creator into Disney Plus.
If you have a Disney Plus account, they
should let you make your own shorts of
up to like three minutes and then
publish them to the site and people
could vote on them and maybe you could
win prizes or get a ticket to Disneyland
or something in exchange for doing it.
But people were making Spider-Man versus
the X-Men and it was like trending on
X.com today. It was very interesting. So
I think that's what I hope for you is
that maybe you can create a model that
helps them make more money. Like I would
think even bigger right now you're
thinking about the tool. I would think
about the ecosystem as well. Selling the
tool is interesting. Creating a new
ecosystem based on what you know is
insane.
So maybe you need to find somebody or
maybe you could buy some old IP and then
you could prove it by making your own
ecosystem and allowing consumers to make
their own content and sharing the
revenue. This is a very interesting
idea. I like the bigger idea of you
maybe being in the IP business somehow
or creating the marketplace of IP. Very
interesting. There's an expression uh
come for the tool, stay for the
marketplace. So you have the tool. I
wonder what the marketplace is here is.
Very interesting idea.
>> Yeah, I think it's
>> you also seem very talented. Each all
three entrepreneurs are very good. Let's
give them a big round of applause. All
three great entrepreneurs. It's hard to
rank these um especially since they're
so desperate, like very different
businesses. Um, but if you told me I
could only invest in one, I probably
would go for Arabot because it's the
crazy of the moment, you know, uh,
startup because everybody needs minerals
now and there's a shortage of rare
earths or, you know, it seems like
there's so much momentum in that space,
right? So, very interesting. All right.
So, now we're going to have eight
companies who are going to pitch. But to
make it efficient, they get two minutes
each and they're going to go four backto
back and then Yuki, since you don't
haven't seen these, you can start you
ask like whichever top two you want to
ask questions to. But we're going to let
them go in a row so that we can but you
got to take notes. It's very important
we take notes because you'll forget the
start of three startups ago. Okay, so
lightning round. Here we go.
>> Hello everyone. My name is Yoske from
Collier. We are building the AI agent or
turning the conversation data into your
business growth. Millions of
conversation happen every day. But what
if someone could uncover insight and act
on them? Alex, a game marketing manager
had just launched a new mobile game. He
invest a lot for new user acquisition,
but player leaves easily. He is
overwhelmed by the tons of conversation
from the users and not sure what really
happened there.
Complens analyzes all the conversation
across the platform and just find out
the rising frustration from a users and
there is a 52 high value players at the
risk of churning. So Alex se this
segment and I turn on our AI agent and
the agent started to conversation with
the users automatically with a
personalized messages and then while
talking to users the agent try to
understand the user needs and the com
lens platform turn this conversation
data into career business intelligence
and also the action plan for Alex. Based
on this insight, the team provide a hot
fix road map better matchmaking system
and this improve the user engagement and
the in-game revenue.
So our business model combine the
service friction and based pricing based
on the conversation volume. Then so far
we have the four paid customer across
Asia market and a training K ML from a
global gaming publisher and a consumer
blends and so far we have 100 paid
customer retention ratio since last
year.
And now the market as long as have the
conversation data this is our scope. We
start to focus on the gaming market and
enter into the other industry and the
region to achieve the hund00 million by
2030.
Team member I used to work at the meta
global gaming team as a marketing
specialist and my CTO also have the
strong background of the engineering
across fintech and AI. Then we are
backed by uh am investor Shimadasang. uh
he's the executive director of the rock
before. That's all my presentation.
Thank you.
>> I'm Hiomiito, founder and inventor of
Juju. We gave protein structure.
This is protein and this is fat. Let me
show you the concept.
Our patented technology combines protein
and fat keeping their boundaries intact.
Decor
thick naturally
about whole cuts in seconds.
New proteins are everywhere but turning
them into a greater steak takes
structure plant fermentation
cultivated four sources of future
protein.
Beyond meat steak f shows the
opportunity beyond grand meat whole cuts
3D printing explorers structure in the
lab.
The question is how to deliver it at
scale.
These are potential customers. They make
the protein. Juju give it give it
structure. A major Japanese food company
has invited us to demonstrate hybrid
meat. You may have eaten their food.
Jason, you may also have two before.
Absolutely.
The
real meat transplant plant protein will
lean and fat kept visibly distinct.
If successful, imagine this company
alone reaching billions of meals with a
5 cent royalty.
We license structuring technology. Hood
companies produce meals. We are
recovering royalties as productions
growth.
Our vision reaches beyond earth
structuring without relying on gravity
even on the moon. We give the proteins
of the future the structure people love.
Juju the structure layer for the protein
ecosystem. Thank you.
>> Hello. We are building Japan media.
Japan media is a m platform that combine
manga and anime creation with global
distribution.
Our traction we had 400k dollars last
year in four months and this year we
forecast $1.8 $8 million and we have
already 200k booked and we have already
330,000 Japanese existing titles
and the world market demand is extremely
exploding but supply cannot keep up.
Every year over 10% of manga anime
creator has been disappearing from the
industry because labor intensive work
low wages. So the world wants Japanese
content, but we can only supply 7% of
anime.
Japan media can make mang make manga and
anime 10x faster and one fifth cost cut.
And the most outstanding point is
corporate company can own their IP. So
far it it has been it has been
impossible.
This is our AI tool. You have only you
have to do is just chat with AI agent
and the AI agent agent can make manga
and adapt into anime after that
translated into 10 languages and
distributed all over the world including
Netflix, Amazon Prime and this is our
works and uh so you can see the most our
concern is to keep originality keep
originality creativeness. This is so ex
extremely difficult for any other AI
tools
and we have already 330,000 Japanese IP
licenses and some of them are in good
revenue
and we are going to adapt into anime.
These famous in Japan anime Japan anime.
So ordinary manga can make money twice
as much as twice much as in revenue and
our team. So almost all our team used to
wanted become manga anime creator but we
couldn't make it because like we cannot
draw or we can story so we founded my
company. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Hi I am Dave Fu co-founder of twin
AI. We are here to scale your
intelligence.
So when I was working for AOL, we used
to buy many small startups such as Ang
Gadget and Autoblog
and when we buy those startups is an
exit for that startup and basically the
entire team leaves and I was left to
maintain that software. What a
nightmare.
So we are building AI twins for software
developers to capture their thinking
process before it's lost due to employee
turnover.
We have our own algorithm called RLPF
which is reinforcement learning with
personal feedback.
Our AI twin can meta prompts AI tools
such as cloud code.
Tech lead love our product and so do
universities.
Our AI twin can be deployed locally or
in the cloud.
Technical depth is a well-known problem
and now VIP coding just makes it worse
and it's compounding.
Andrew, Tim Draper and Reed Hoffman
already have their AI twins. Is Jason
and Yuki joining them next?
I'm an ambassador for deep learning.AI
and we I have been organizing many AI
events and we have a natural market that
we can sell our twin to. Our
twin has each of them has their own
model that it fine-tunes
and we are working towards personal AGI.
My co-founder, she loves the design and
she wants her twin to do creative work
for her. Let's end this with a demo.
Hello. I can't help but notice the space
in your throws
like how can I assist you today? Are we
working layouts or the house as they
show in a mist?
>> Thank you. Let's pretend that uh you and
I are deciding Yuki who we're going to
accept to Tech Stars or to launch or
found a university. And so we're inside
the private room and you guys all get to
hear the comments. Sound good? Okay.
Which one is your we absolutely have to
accept this
>> because the founder
and the
the founder product combination is so
strong. Which one did you just love the
founder and their energy and the
product? We saw four great ones,
>> right?
>> Which one? Customer conversations
analyzing them. Crazia 3D printed stakes
with Juju Juju Juju and then Japan Media
AI tools for making magna at manga at a
tenth of the cost or David from soon AI
creating digital twins of founders who
have left companies
>> to bring them back from the grave.
Which one did you think has the most
upside and you just thought wow this
founder is going to just work really
hard and make it happen? It's hard to
pick and then also I have to uh disclose
that Japan media Yuko was a textures
company
>> but I would uh go with uh uh uh Japan
media still.
>> I mean it it was for me the one I
thought the founder had great energy and
the product was awesome. Let's give her
a big round of applause. I think it is
the one that is the most the quickest
path to having revenue, scaling revenue,
and an obvious idea. We were just
talking in the previous presentations
about, oh, people are making Marvel
characters. Wonder if that could be
inside of Disney. And then here we go.
Here's an AI tool for making manga.
Yeah. And other things, uh, comic books,
etc. And she's already made the tool.
And she has no problem with
>> that she's made a tool to do it. A lot
of people who are outside the industry
or inside the industry are like, "We
can't do that. We're not allowed to make
that tool. We have to go with artists
and this is sacriiggious." And she
didn't have that concern, right?
>> She's like, "Oh, more people get to make
more interesting things. Here we go."
And it's just another tool. And I
believe that that is like the original
criticism of
uh CGI, computer graphics, was, "Oh,
this isn't real." like the Disney
artists were very upset about Pixar and
it was like, well, Pixar makes really
great content. It's still very creative,
right? So, I really like your business.
Um, and uh I like that you have
different ways to monetize it. I think
you got to get rid of the old business
maybe
>> and just be focused on this new tool in
business and make it simpler to
understand for investors how that
marketplace actually makes money.
>> Agreed. Agreed.
>> Yeah, the market is growing. Too much
going on to understand what the real
business is. Which one do you think will
get customers and money?
>> Customers and money.
>> Crazier. Crazy.
>> Yeah, that was mine as well. Explain why
that's so obvious that they're going to
get customers quickly.
>> Why do you think that's
>> why do I think so? Um, I mean, they
already have the four enterprise
customers. Uh, so they approved like,
you know, initial pro market fit. Uh, so
they just need to expand into what they
have discovered through customers. Um,
but I I think the this is sort of like a
like a kind of easy play to sell. Uh,
I'm not sure if it's going to scale to
an expansional degree, but uh, in terms
of customer finding an initial growth, I
think, uh, crazy
>> Japan media looks like it could scale to
the moon, right? It could catch fire.
Um, but it's going to take a little bit
of time. And then Crazia looks like
you're going to really quickly get
customers, but how big can it get?
because it seems like such an obvious
idea to study the chat room, right? Uh
yeah, and then have the chat room,
>> right?
>> Uh give you ideas and then do customer
surveys
using AI. And it also feels like anybody
could build it, right? So you're going
to really have to make a very good
product so that people don't roll their
own because you could ask Claude to just
make it for you, right?
>> Yes. And so that is the challenge is
like why are they going to buy it from
you if they can make their own bespoke
software? It's a really high benchmark
for SAS products today. Uh all right. So
I think we're both in alignment on that.
And then you have to ask yourself, okay,
the wild card. We always talk about wild
cards when we're putting together a
class. And we have two crazy wild cards
here. One of them wants to make 3D
printed steaks. Yum yum. Uh with great
marbilization. That's a crazy idea.
Nobody's really made that work. and the
other one wants to make digital clones
so that when you buy stuff and there's
actually a company bending spoons in
Italy that's been buying up all these
old assets and their core premise is the
company had 200 people they get it down
to 20 it had 20 people they get it down
to four and they use AI to automate
everything and make it profitable
>> so they can take loans out to buy the
products and if they interesting
>> yeah so it's kind of interesting so
which of those two do you like for your
wild hard digital twin or 3D stakes.
>> Uh digital twin. Okay.
>> Uh I I have um actually angel invested
in the cultivated meat company before
and I think it's hard regulatory. Yeah.
Um Hardles is really hard and then I
think industry is not uh doing well
>> in general. So regardless of their
amazing technology and whatnot, I
>> Yeah. Even if they have the best thing,
they have the biggest mountain to climb.
I too went with the digital twin. That
seemed like an easy one. Okay, let's
give a big round of applause for our
first group. They did great.
And let's do four more. I'm Jacob from
Roomite. Uh we are focused on AI server.
Uh right now uh AI server has a big
challenge as we know uh the AI chips
gotten faster and faster. So moving the
data between the chips is very
limitation. So the fundamental PCB
inside AI server is limiting the data of
the data trans data transfer. So this is
causing a few problem.
Okay. At lumin light we developed a
solution to data transferring of the
ball of the PCB ball and direct at high
speed uh create a new direct high speed
pace between the GPU and GPU. Doing so
we are able to increase the four time
speed with our first generation product
is on my hand right now. This is not a
TV cable. This is real product. and our
second generation uh uh in can increase
the speed over eight times uh will plan
to the launch next year Q2. This is
going to revolutionize the way the AI
server are build the AI server of the
tomorrow will not look like the same as
the AI server today.
Okay, with the direct of the B pace uh
we can do this and maintain a clear
signal with a 50% low signal loss than
reverent PCP. This is a major not a
simulate
and we already have the customer engaged
right now. We have a four customer
engaged two in Taiwan, one in US. I
cannot name the name. I'm sure you
recognize the few player we are talking
to.
and we build and we measure and now we
are going to win the platform and I'm
franchising right now to get through our
initial production line and able for the
conclusion of a PC with a major server
manufacturers at both tier one tier two
level we are getting a lot of
interesting right now and are looking
for the right investor that are willing
to join our uh journey uh to build up
the super fast AI infrastructure around
the world. Thank you.
>> Nice to meet you. I'm Me, co-ounder of
We are building Genji. Genji is
immersive experience platform service.
Shopping has become very convenient.
Uh but we lost something freedom of
discovering feeling the real culture
with their eyes and ears. Millions of
overseas Japanese pop culture fans want
to come to Japan and get item only
available in Japan but cannot. Why?
because travel time cost physical
limitations. That's why we developed the
Genji. Genji is platform service. So
Genji lets you achieve your goals
remotely through local worker acting on
your behalf uh and sharing uh while
sharing site hearing and touch.
How to request is like Uber on a map.
You can choose a specific location,
time, task and we will assign the local
worker as your avatar. So then you can
send me teleport there. This is
happening in real time and you are in
Japan. Now if you click the direction
button you can move in that direction
like this. If you click the screen you
can close to the item. If you press the
A button or Y button you can grab the
item and you can purchase it. can so
bring their personal immersive
experience for you without physical
trouble. Unique point first is platform
service their response through hyon
gaming UI system and the certified d
payment approved. We already some some
traction and global patents.
This is a global partners.
Our special team uh has a special
technical skill and we all have mission
to eliminate global inequality.
We are seeking investor and strategic
partner collaboration with uh for PC. So
thank you very much. We create a world
everyone can move freely live
authentically and get access to
opportunity no matter where you are.
Thank you very much.
>> Wow. Very good. Holy cow.
That is crazy. I want to do it.
>> Hi everyone, I'm Shivangi and we're
Tatwa Silicon. This is the problem we're
solving.
First cut analog circuit design takes
months and it costs $10,000 for one
circuit. We want to fix that. Shivraj is
a senior analog circuit design engineer
and he wants a first cut design of a 12-
bit SAR ADC with 100 mega samples per
second on 180 nanometers. So he types it
in. Our agent confirms if all his
specifications are correct and then he
runs the design. He goes through his
entire workflow starting with
architecture, device sizing, math and
trade-offs. He can also inspect all the
waveforms and he gets a DRC report. He
can go back and change the
specifications, try 50 mega samples per
second and a new architecture is
instantly generated.
He can look at all the activity logs of
the agent and he can ask how to
understand the reasoning behind it just
like talking to a senior colleague.
This used to take more than three months
before this and now it takes less than a
day. We're already validating in three
ways. We have a design pilot and they've
already reached accuracy of 90%. We also
have a procurement champion and silicon
validation access. We're going to be
charging for each user annually $15,000
to $150,000 and more for enterprises
depending on this type of license. Our
team consists of myself and experts from
analog AI as well as enterprise
security. We're Tata Silicon and we're
cutting analog circuit design cycles
from months to days. Thank you.
>> All right. Very well done.
Wow.
So many great companies.
>> Hello everyone. My name is Ana. I'm the
founder of Mimi AI Japanese learning
app. Meet Hope. She's used Duallingingo
for eight months and despite having full
streaks, she still is unable to actually
order at a restaurant. And that's the
reality of Japanese learning these days.
I get it. As a self-taught Japanese
speaker myself of over 10 years, I've
been sharing my learnings to nearly a
million followers. And I've noticed a
common uh problem. It's that most of
these apps prioritize streaks over
actual fluency. And the result is that
70% of foreign residents in Japan can't
speak Japanese. And we're seeing a real
societal friction.
Mimi fixes this. Mimi.
Mimi is an AI Japanese learning app that
puts you into real situations like a
convenience store or your first day at
work. and actually goes through the
conversations and talks to you, fixes
your issues in real time so that you're
able to actually speak Japanese with
confidence. And just like that, Hope is
actually able to speak Japanese and no
app has achieved this before. Uh our
real customer uh has said that it's
really been a practical solution for
them to use as they're studying Japanese
uh especially for output.
Our business model is subscription. So
we do $20 per month and for enterprise
we do $100 per seat.
So far, we have one customer, 30 users,
and about $20 of revenue to date. And
looking against our competitors, Mimi is
truly the outstanding option, especially
with the kinds of tools and study
methods we have. Before creating Mimi, I
validated this core idea by creating a
beginner Japanese course and we've done
about a thousand students and 100K in
revenue. Uh, in order to achieve our
users, uh, I will utilize my social
media podcasts as well as focus on
productled growth.
So for revenue, we're expecting in the
first year about a,000 MAU with about
240k in revenue and 24 million over the
next three years.
In order to achieve 100 million, we
would need about 225 MAU and 50 uh
enterprise contracts.
Our bottomup TAM is focused on the total
Japanese learning market and that's
about 960 million.
And as a Japanese learner myself, I have
the highest Japanese language
certification and have led marketing at
Amazon. And that was Mimi AI Japanese
learning app. Thank you.
>> All right. Well done.
I have seen this pitch before and it
gets better every time. Um
I just have to say like sometimes I see
a startup and I go wow that is just
crazy and awesome and fun and that for
me was uh Geni. Um the company is Toru
Toru. But letting people
watch a person walk around Akihabara
and going to different stores is
mind-blowing and then to buy it and then
they put it in a box and send it to you
is insane
and fun. And there's a very famous um
science fiction author William Gibson
and he said the street finds its use for
technology. Um and this is an example of
the street finding its use for streaming
technology and e-commerce and location
data and smartphones. And who knows when
you say you can rent this person for $30
an hour to go shopping for you what
people will have them do.
I might actually have a person do this
and just have them go eat the French
toast I like and then send the video to
my friend and say, "Go get this French
toast." Or like I might have them go
look for weird stuff in Akihabara on
like the seventh floor and yeah, just
for fun with my daughters and watch them
run around town. And it's like almost
like entertainment and it reminds me of
the live streaming that we're seeing now
in China that people are doing for
shopping that's now they're trying to
make it work at Amazon. But there's
something very interesting here and I I
I'm really intrigued by it. It's like a
virtual task rabbit in another culture.
And I could see it working in France and
New York and other places for rich
people to go have people do weird things
and buy stuff for them.
It's insane and crazy and I like it.
What did you like in this group of four?
>> Uh yeah, I like that too. Uh the only
thing I had about the company was um uh
how they make money. They they say 120
90k uh revenue.
>> You take 30% of uh the hourly fee. Is
that how you make money? Revenue share.
>> Revenue share with merchandise.
>> Oh, with the merchandise, too. Oh,
>> or I Yeah.
>> Oh, that's interesting. Got it. So, you
take 20% on top of the
>> what's sold. Is that what you do?
>> I think so. Yeah, I think so.
>> Interesting.
>> So, I'm Yeah, it's very like Japan uh
like app or, you know, product, but I'm
not sure if it works in the United
States, for example.
>> I'm not sure it does.
>> You go through Walmart or Target and see
something.
>> Yeah. See the stuff that came from China
to Yeah. to America. Very strange.
>> Yeah.
>> And then I'd like if I can continue uh
uh I like Remy lights, but I have quick
question. Where are they made? Okay,
understood. So, everything is made
Taiwan. All parts procured in Taiwan.
>> Okay, understood.
>> Yeah, I mean I there's a lot of
innovation happening with chips. Two of
the four presentations here uh in this
last group were doing chips and I um the
last the second to last company Tativa
Silicon, we got to rename it. Um that is
something people are doing in the United
States. People are ordering,
you know, circuit boards and chips and
making all kinds of bespoke hardware now
thanks to the ability to build it in AI
and then ship it and then people will
make five boards and send it to you and
sometimes it works and sometimes it
doesn't and if it doesn't work you take
$100 in boards and throw it in the
garbage and then you order it again.
It's incredible. The world is nuts right
now.
>> So physical AI. Yeah, definitely the So
the validation I think is key. And then
she mentioned 90% accuracy. So if it
goes like about 95 99 I think it's yeah
very promising.
>> Well and just what will people be able
to do? Like what won't people be able to
do? Like you're going to be able to
people are making there there's also
companies in the United States now that
are doing CAD. You can just send a CAD
drawing and we'll send you something
fabricated in aluminum or steel or
whatever you're making. So you send them
like somebody just made like a door for
their dog to get in and out of their
house and they just custom fabricated
it. They made it in 3D and then it came
to their house in parts and they put it
together.
>> Like the world's nuts right now, right,
>> Yuki? It's crazy
>> what's going on out here in these
streets.
>> I like to know.
>> You can just make anything.
>> It's nuts.
>> All right. You have a favorite in this
group? Like if you were going to accept
him into tech stars, you'd be like,
"Okay, this makes a lot of sense." like
or this is a crazy one that I'm gonna
take a risk on one of my slots with
because it's an outlier. What's your
crazy outlier? What's your layup? Like a
layup in basketball is like an easy
shot. Which one is the easy get to
revenue quickly? You know, has a good
chance of getting further investment.
And then which one's the crazy one?
>> Crazy one is roomy light, I think. Uh I
mean the hardware manufacturing is
tough. uh uh but if they can build uh
and they massproduce what they say they
can uh I think it's a a gigantic uh uh
company and a crazy idea. The other
three I think it's pretty similar uh in
my opinion uh Ana did a great job in
presenting but if it's only Japanese I
think the market is probably too small
so you do need to think you know how to
expand into other languages. Yeah, I'm
gonna go with Genshi as my crazy wild
card and then um I would give it to
Mimi, but uh since they went through
Founder University, I shouldn't vote for
you. So, I'm going to take you out and
then I'm going to make my um one that I
think is got a straight shot is Tat TV.
I think like a lot of people are going
to really want that. But I also really
think Lights and a Chance to make some
big money.
>> So, I like it as like a big money play.
like what if it works
>> and then they they that a company like
that will get bought very quickly in my
experience.
>> Right.
>> Right. Like they'll be like if if it's
like a really good team and they made a
really innovative product, Jensen or
>> AMD is going to be like we need that
team. We need that innovation.
>> TSMC, somebody's going to just snap it
up. Yeah.
>> At some point.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> both are Taiwanese too. So yeah.
>> Exactly. Yeah. both Taiwanese
entrepreneurs.